Call of the Forest

Jonathan Reading Yoga Teacher

	07958 364166
	jon@calloftheforest.com
0	www.calloftheforest.com

Practice

I share the timeless teachings of Hatha yoga, inspired by the tradition of TKV Desikachar. My focus is on personal inquiry, inviting individuals to tune into their inner experience and discover new ways of moving and relating to themselves. I teach 1-2-1 as well as in a group setting.

This is a holistic practice that incorporates:

- Slow conscious movement
- Functional movement patterns
- Movement synchronised with breath
- Breathing practices
- Meditation

•

With the aim to:

- Integrate body, breath and mind
- Identify and re-pattern dysfunctional movement patterns
- · Improve body awareness and coordination
- Release unconscious tension
- · Tune into sensations, feelings and emotions
- Discover freedom and ease within the body
- Reduce stress and anxiety

.

Currently I am training under the guidance of Colin Dunsmuir on a 4 yoga year therapy training course.

RYT 200

March 2017

Education and Certification

Teacher Training and Yoga Therapy 2019 - 2022

True Yoga, London

Karma Yoga Program March - May 2018 Hyridaya yoga, Mazunte, Mexico BSC Multimedia Technology First Class 2003 - 2005 Nottingham Trent University

Hatha Yoga World, Rishikesh, India

Art of Viniyoga

September - December 2017 Sadhana Mala, Brighton

Teaching Experience

Private Yoga Teacher April 2017 – Present

Other Work Experience

Freelance Developer 2013 – Present